<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Andrew Cox</title>
  <id>http://andrewcox.org</id>
  <link href="http://andrewcox.org"/>
  <link href="http://andrewcox.org/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-01-07T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Andrew Cox</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Actively seeking employment</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://andrewcox.org/2016/01/08/actively-seeking-employment/"/>
    <id>http://andrewcox.org/2016/01/08/actively-seeking-employment/</id>
    <published>2016-01-07T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-09T16:33:13-05:00</updated>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the first time since I graduated college in 2001, I am actively looking for a new job. This has given me a rare opportunity to be more introspective about what I want in a job. Like a rock skipping across a river, I’ve dipped into and out of development...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the first time since I graduated college in 2001, I am actively looking for a new job. This has given me a rare opportunity to be more introspective about what I want in a job. Like a rock skipping across a river, I’ve dipped into and out of development for the last 15 years. I’ve worked at a variety of companies from small to large, consumer products to enterprise software. Now I think I have a pretty good idea of the kind of environment I thrive in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about what I bring to the table, check out my &lt;a href="/about-me"&gt;About Me&lt;/a&gt; page and my &lt;a href="/resume/"&gt;résumé&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in priority order, are what I want in my next job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="1-team"&gt;1. Team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to work with people who are better than me.&lt;/strong&gt; I want my next gig to stretch me technically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="2-culture"&gt;2. Culture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to work at a fun, user-centric, continuous improvement company.&lt;/strong&gt; Culture is a broad category and I &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; put it above the &lt;strong&gt;Team&lt;/strong&gt;, but I’ve worked at a company with a mediocre culture and a great team, and the awesome team trumped the mixed-bag culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="3-process"&gt;3. Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id="4-technology-stack"&gt;4. Technology Stack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id="5-leadership"&gt;5. Leadership&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id="6-product"&gt;6. Product&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
